Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Capstone Archives AD.MC.004
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Social Sciences Division Projects, 2014-2019
  - Social Research and Public Policy
    - Imran, Rabiya. Women and Pakistani Sharia: A Case Study of Khula Laws, 2019; 2019-0209 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0209)
      How is Sharia contextualized when granting rights to women in the post-colonial context? How is it used by courts in South Asia in terms of divorce? This paper looks at khula case law from the Lahore High Court in Pakistan and the Punjab and Haryana High Court in India to examine the role that Sharia plays in the decision-making process of the courts. My analysis examines eighteen cases from the Lahore High Court and five from the Punjab and Haryana Court in detail. I argue that in both India and Pakistan, Sharia and Islam are being utilized to create rights for women in the realm of divorce, where they don't exist through non-Islamic means. I also argue that in the Lahore High Court, the court uses language that is filled with Islamic symbolism to grant legitimacy to its decisions that are favorable to women. However, this symbolism is not found at the Punjab and Haryana High Court. To make sense of this variation, I argue, Shariah is used as a reliable device in both Islamic and non-Islamic contexts to achieve similar results, albeit with varying motivations.
    - Jo, Atoka. The Use of Pseudonym, Team Composition and Identity in Cryptocurrency, 2019; 2019-0198 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0198)
      Satoshi Nakamoto is known as the founder of Bitcoin and the pioneer of cryptocurrency. Yet, until this day, no one knows who Satoshi Nakamoto is or whom the name represents. Because of him, the usage of pseudonyms among members of cryptocurrency companies has gained popularity. This paper will explore how team composition and identity affects the usage of pseudonyms among the cryptocurrency company members. Team composition and identity will be broken down to three components of publicity, technical roles, and gender of the cryptocurrency company members. By investigating the relationship between team composition and identity and the usage of pseudonyms, the study will demonstrate how pseudonyms can be used not only to hide one's identity, but also to augment one's identity.
    - Karan, Filip. Pre-exposure Prophylaxis (PrEP): a Miracle Drug or a Moral Hazard?, 2019; 2019-0180 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0180)
      Little is known about the way in which taking pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) affects sexual behavior and sexual health outcomes of men-who-have-sex-with-men (MSM). I examine these outcomes by using Facebook, Grindr and the Gay Ad Network as recruitment sites, linking ads to a questionnaire which 1823 US-based MSM completed. Using a series of one-sided t-tests, I find that MSM who are on PrEP have significantly more sexual partners, are more likely to be involved in concurrent relationships, use condoms less frequently and report higher incidences of bacterial STDs than MSM who are not on PrEP. I then use propensity score matching to control for a set of demographic and behavioral characteristics associated with PrEP use to estimate the effect of taking PrEP on the above-mentioned outcomes. I again find statistically significant results for all outcomes. Lastly, I employ a conjoint experiment to compare how MSM who are on PrEP compare to those who are not on PrEP make partner-selection decisions. I find that MSM on PrEP do not take the number of their partner's previous sexual relationships nor their condom use into account to make this decision, while those who are not on PrEP do.
    - Karpauskaite, Ruta. NETWORKS OF INFLUENCE Think Tank Behavior, Relationships and Bias in Washington DC, 2019; 2019-0173 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0173)
      The current debates around the use of money in politics and the amount of foreign influence in Washington DC have brought the unique role of think tanks under increased scrutiny due to their potential to channel both effects. While think tanks, in theory, are supposed to produce unbiased policy analysis and help promote informed debate--criticism of think tanks often alleges that they are far from unbiased. While such literature has attempted to delineate this problem, most of the research has focused on external analysis of think tanks as part of the larger policymaking system. Leveraging ethnographic research conducted within the think tank community itself rather than externally, my analysis questions the consensus view that think tank behavior is largely driven by seeking policy impact; instead finding that think tank behavior is conducted according to internal and external relationships. With a greater understanding of think tank behavior, I seek to better understand the origin of bias and how it materializes in think tanks' most visible output - external research.
    - Mahne, Matilda. Change in Peacebuilding Diplomacy: A Case Study of Finland, 2019; 2019-0140 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0140)
      In 2008, Finland created a National Action Plan for the implementation of the United Nations Security Council resolution on Women, Peace and Security that was unanimously adopted in October 2000. The resolution was significant as it was the first of its kind to specifically address women's role in conflict and peacebuilding. Though Finland has been on the forefront of the peacebuilding scene for years, the country shaped its action plan for the resolution a few years later than many other states. This research project looks deeper into this foreign policy change and endeavours to answer the following question: why did Finland adopt its National Action Plan for the United Nations Security Council Resolution on Women, Peace and Security in 2008? By looking into policy documents and speeches, as well as drawing from public debate and previous literature on foreign policy change and policy diffusion, I find that the Finnish case warrants a multi-layered explanation: using the policy diffusion mechanisms of learning, competition, coercion and emulation, the drive for Finnish foreign policy change has taken place on three distinct levels (international, regional, and civil society), where the three levels mutually created the condition for change.
    - Malik, Warda. Religion, State, and Nation: Claims to Citizenship Among Pakistan's Ahmadiyya Community, 2019; 2019-0186 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0186)
      This research focuses on Pakistan's Ahmadiyya community, who self-identity as Muslims but the state recognises them as a non-Muslim minority, to demonstrate how the state narratives about inclusion in Pakistan have been used to exclude and reduce this community to the status of second-class citizens. Most of the existing literature has focused on how the Pakistani nation- state has constructed its imagined community based on exclusionary citizenship, but little is said about the grievances that the marginalised have from the state and what it can teach us about national citizenship. Given the exclusion of Ahmadis from Pakistan's national discourse, I have conducted twelve semi-structured interviews with community members and conducted an analysis of op-ed articles in an alternative media publication to understand counter-narratives of Ahmadis in relation to the dominant narratives of state. This research focuses on counter-narratives of Ahmadis about Pakistani identity in order to broaden our understanding of identity through a focus on the excluded citizen rather than the State. The research sheds light on what national identity looks like when viewed through the lens of exclusion.
    - Olson, Erik. Neither Here nor There: Non-political transnationalism amongst Bosnian refugee families and the blurring of migrant taxonomies, 2019; 2019-0172 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0172)
      Third-country resettlement is one of the UN's three "durable solutions" made available to refugees worldwide. While millions have benefitted from such programmes, there remains a gap in knowledge concerning the long-term effects of resettlement on the experiences of refugees. At the same time, migration studies literature has established a dichotomy between voluntary and involuntary migrants. Here, a tendency is shown which views connections to people in places in the country of origin as distinctly political in form and motivation. This essay takes a transnationalist approach to studying the experiences of Bosnian refugee families resettled to Boise, Idaho, USA during and immediately after the Bosnian War (1992-1995). Focusing on transnational practices developed by refugees over two decades in the United States, my analysis questions the prevailing image of refugees as inherently political transnational actors. This study investigates non-political forms of refugee transnationalism by examining patterns of ownership and flows of goods, funds, and people between Boise and Bosnia. In doing so, I seek to blur the lines between traditional migrant taxonomies and contribute to a more holistic understanding of the refugee as an informed and empowered international actor.
    - Szekeres, Melinda. Navigating Entrepreneurship: The Role of Law in Organizational Emergence in the UAE, 2019; 2019-0171 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0171)
      This project observes the law and policy that govern entrepreneurship in the UAE, comparing it, empirically, to the lived experiences of entrepreneurs on the ground. I observe entrepreneurship as a novel work environment that offers starkly different experiences for UAE nationals and residents alike. The distinction, primarily, manifests in the levels of ease of organizational emergence for both groups. I suggest that the UAE offers a quasi-experimental insight into the two different pools of entrepreneurs that result by having a 'high' or 'low' bar—the former for residents and the latter for nationals. In comparing the experiences of entrepreneurs emerging across these two pools, this capstone asks whether a more 'helpful' legal and institutional environment increases the success the rates of entrepreneurial ventures. Based on its finding that the increased ease of starting up is not necessarily an advantage, this study complicates the theoretical assumption that low barriers to starting up are necessarily always preferred because they lead to a higher aggregate entrepreneurial activity.
    - Wong, Theros. The Power of Ethnic Politics in Foreign Policy Making Decisions: A Comparison of Malaysia's Mahathir and the Philippines' Duterte in the Belt Road Initiative, 2019; 2019-0196 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0196)
      Malaysia's rejection of China's Belt Road Initiative came as a shock to the international community. In order to understand the driving forces behind this rejection, this research created a structured approach to examine plausible factors that could lead to this policy decision, including the economic, geopolitics and domestic factors. Upon examining these factors in comparison to the Philippines, which accepted the Belt Road investments, I conclude that domestic ethnic politics act as a catalyst to Prime Minister Mahathir's decision.
    - Yu, Alyssa. Post Generation: Social Media Use of WeChat and Facebook by Chinese and American College Students, 2019; 2019-0179 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0179)
      This project is a comparative study of contemporary social media usage of both Chinese and American social media sites by Chinese and American NYUSH freshmen conducted through mixed methods of social media content analysis and interviews. Ultimately, this paper seeks to better understand the extent to which technological features, cultural backgrounds, and pre-existing and new networks influence social interactions online.
    - Zubareva, Anastasiia. Fostering refugee-inclusion: the role of self-affirmation and perspective-taking, 2019; 2019-0158 (E-records AD-MC-004, Folder 2019-0158)
      This research has tested the role of self-affirmation and perspective-taking tasks in fostering inclusive intergroup behavior and motivating the respondents to provide help and assistance to Syrian refugees. The experiment was conducted with a sample of working age and retired Canadians, outside the laboratory. During the experiment the participants have completed either self-affirmation task, perspective-taking task, combination of both tasks, or participated in a control condition before answering the measures of attitudes and perceived threat towards Syrian refugees and participating in the behavioral task measuring the respondents' readiness to support this outgroup. Results show that self-affirmation and combined intervention were effective in fostering inclusive behavior towards the outgroup. This study has also found that the middle aged respondents had less malleable views, and were less likely to be motivated to change their behavior by a one-time intervention. The participants between 35-54 years of age were more likely to hold strong unfavorable views of Syrian refugees due to the perceived competition over finite resources and welfare benefits in Canada. This paper also draws further implications for the researchers and policymakers.
- Other Capstone Documentation, 2016-2019 (E-records cds-asc)
  Other Capstone Documentation includes acquired audio and video from Divisional Capstone Festivals, student presentations about their projects, and other materials that are about Capstones but are not documents of the projects themselves. Includes digital photos, videos, and slides.
  - Arts & Humanities Capstone Festivals and Exhibitions, 2014-2020; 2 Terabytes (E-records cds-asc)
    Includes audiovisual materials (photos, posters, films, filmed performances) associated with Arts and Humanities Division student Capstone Projects. These files were either documented by AV Library team members, or acquired from the Division.
    Arrangement
    Files are arranged by academic year, and then a simple alphabetical list of digital files is included in the scope and contents for each year. Due to the high volume of files, the physical digital folders that make up each year's Capstone Festival have not been renamed or reorganized, and remain in the state in which they were received. The list allows for discoverability and accessibility.
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Documentation, 2014; 96.81 Gigabytes (E-records cds-asc)
      Unprocessed List of Digital Contents for 2014 Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival:
      ADAM: REALFINAL1.mov REALFINAL2.mov REALFINAL3.mov REALFINAL4 (withphonesound).mov REALFINAL4.mov REALFINAL4(nophonesound).mov
      AMANI: Adam_NYUAD_Festival_ May2nd.mov
      APRIL: APRIL CAPSTONE EXPORT.mov
      AYAZ: AYAZ KAMALOV_SCREENING CAPSTONE FINAL.mov
      BESIK: Besik_Lost in Escapade_screening_may 5.mov
      CHANI: CHANIGATTOAHAB
      MÁTÉ AND NOLAN: allison boyfriend boyfriend.mov allison boyfriend william.mov allison no boyfriend leave.mov allison no boyfriend stay.mov william no ring drink.mov william no ring hand.mov william ring no ring.mov william ring ring.mov
- Unprocessed 2020 Capstone Projects and other documentation (E-records cds-asc)
  Capstone Projects from 2020, and other Capstone-related audiovisual files, are acquired but unprocessed as of the publication of this finding aid. For more information about access, contact Archives and Special Collections.